Well, something like that,
好的，类似的东西，
hey, welcome to session eleven,
嘿，欢迎来到第十一节课，
we're going to talk about pentatonic scales,
我们要讲的是五音音阶，
guitar player's favorite scale that he needs to know,
吉他演奏者最喜欢的音阶，他需要知道，
in order to do good old fashioned rock and roll soloing,
才能做好老式摇滚乐独奏，
so many things have started with pentatonic scales,
很多东西都是从五音音阶开始的，
and that's what we're going to talk about today.
这就是我们今天要讨论的。
Pentatonic scales are the foundation of soloing,
五声音阶是独奏的基础，
so we're going to learn about the five pentatonic forms
所以我们将学习五种五声音阶形式，
as well as some common soloing patterns,
以及一些常见的独奏模式，
for you to get started on,
让你可以开始，
in our guitar tips section,
在我们的吉他技巧部分，
we're going to talk about learning
我们将谈论如何学习，
how to play and solo in any key, any place on the neck
如何在任何[调]上，在琴颈上任何地方演奏和独奏，
by connecting pentatonic scales,
通过连接五声音阶，
the most, one of the most valuable keys, I've ever learned.
我所学过的最有价值的调之一。
So we're going to add a new section
所以我们将增加一个新的部分，
on developing your musical ears
关于发展你的音乐耳朵，
to be able to play the ideas, that you hear in your head,
以便能够弹奏你在大脑中听到的想法，
a little bit about ear training,
一些耳朵训练，
training our ears to hear what our mind is telling us to play,
训练我们的耳朵听到我们的大脑告诉我们要演奏什么，
so we've got to go,
所以我们得开始了，
let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Okay, today, we're gonna talk about pentatonic scales,
好的，今天我们将讨论五声音阶，
pentatonic scales are one of the most useful scales,
五声音阶是最有用的音阶之一，
that you use for good old-fashioned soloing and rock and roll stuff,
你可以用它来演奏老式的独奏和摇滚乐，
pentatonic, as you can tell by the name,
五声，你可以从名字中看出，
penta, it's a five note scale,
penta ，这是一个五音符的音阶，
and it's based off of the major scale,
它是以大调音阶为基础的，
it uses takes certain notes out of that major scale
它使用了大调音阶中的某些音符，
and it forms kind of a mini scale within it,
并在其中形成了一种迷你音阶，
a pentatonic scale, a five note scale.
一个五声音阶，一个五个音符音阶。
So what notes does it take,
那么它使用什么音符，
here we have a C major scale,
这里我们有一个 C 大调音阶，
and the notes are C D E F G A B and C,
音符是 C D E F G A B 和 C ，
now we're going to take the first, the second, the third, the fifth and the sixth step out of that scale
现在我们使用第一个，第二个，第三个，第五个和第六个音阶，
and that's going to form our subset,
这将形成我们的子集，
that we're going to call the pentatonic scale,
我们称之为五声音阶，
the pentatonic scale is made up of the first, the second, the third, the fifth and the sixth of your major scale,
五声音阶由第一个，第二个，第三个，第五个和第六个大调音阶组成，
you take those notes out, whether it's in C F G whatever
你拿出那些音符，不管它是 C F G ，还是什么，
and you take those notes out and that forms a pentatonic scale,
你把这些音符拿出来，形成一个五声音阶，
so a pentatonic scale in C would be C D E G and A,
所以 C 中的五声音阶就是 C D E G A ，
C, D E G and A,
C D E G A ，
of course you keep going, either, on either side of it,
当然，你可以在它的两边继续，
C D E G and A, just keep repeating.
C D E G A ，继续重复。
Now, let's say if we did an F,
现在假如我们做一个 F ，
remember our major scales and our keys that were so hard to learn,
记得我们很难学的大调音阶和音调，
here's where it starts paying off,
这就是它开始奏效的地方，
an F scale, F G A Bb C D E F,
F 音阶， F G A Bb C D E F ，
we're gonna take the one three five six,
我们取 1 3 5 6 ，
one one two three five and six out of that scale,
从音阶中取 1 2 3 5 6 ，
you end up with F G A C and D
最后得到 F G A C D ，
and that makes up an f major pentatonic scale.
这就构成了 F 大调五声音阶。
Now here's one thing we need to talk about,
现在有一件事我们需要讨论，
we talked about parallel major and parallel minor in our chords
我们讨论了和弦中的平行大调和平行小调，
or in our major scales and our natural minor scale,
或者在我们的大调音阶和自然小调音阶中，
that we talked about a couple of sessions back,
我们在前面的几次课程上谈到了，
here it's gonna come, it's gonna rear its ugly head again,
这里它再次来了，
when we start talking about pentatonics,
当我们开始谈论五声音阶的时候，
actually it's not a bad thing, it's a very good thing,
实际上这不是一件坏事，这是一件非常好的事情，
you get two for the price of one,
你可以一举两得，
you can solo in two different keys with only one scale
你可以使用一个音阶在两个不同的调中独奏，
and being a guitar player,
作为一个吉他演奏者，
I like the easiest way I could do it,
我喜欢最简单的方式，
so that's why it starts helping out with that.
所以这就是为什么它开始帮助我们。
So each of these scales,
所以每个音阶，
that we're going to talk about five different forms,
我们将要讨论的五种不同的形式，
each of them are going to have a major root,
每一个都有一个主要的根音，
I could use them in a major key,
我可以在一个大调中使用它们，
I also with a little bit of calculation, can use them in a minor key,
我也可以经过一点计算，在一个小调中使用它们，
so you get two for the price of one,
所以你可以一举两得，
that's what the relationship between parallel major and parallel minor is,
这就是平行大调和平行小调之间的关系，
let's refresh our memory on that,
让我们重新回忆一下，
if I'm thinking major,
如果我想的是大调，
the sixth step of a major scale is gonna be the natural minor,
大调走六步是自然小调，
so if I'm in C
如果我在 C 中，
and I want to know the natural minor or the minor root,
我想知道自然小调或小调根音，
it would be a the six step,
那就是六步，
if I'm in F, it would be D,
如果我在 F ，它就会是 D ，
if I'm in Bb, it would be G.
如果我是 Bb ，那就是 G 。
Okay, if I'm going from minus, go the opposite way,
好的，如果我另一个方向开始，
if I'm going from minor,
如果我从小调开始，
well, then you just have to count up two or go to the minor third,
你只需要数两个或小调第三个，
if I'm Am, remember it would be a C scale starting on A,
如果我是 Am ，它将是从 A 开始的 C 音阶，
then the relative major would be the third step of that A B C,
那么相对大调是第三步， A B C ，
so the c would be the relative major,
所以 C 是相对大调，
from, if I'm looking at it from a minor perspective.
如果我是从小调的角度来看的话。
Now, let's talk about the first pentatonic form,
现在我们来谈谈第一个五音形式，
okay, there are five forms,
好的，有五个形式，
we're going to devote the majority of our time to the first form,
我们将把大部分时间花在第一个形式上，
because that's generally what guitar players like to use,
因为这通常是一个吉他手喜欢使用的，
because we like the easy way and we don't like getting too hard.
因为我们喜欢简单的方式，我们不喜欢变得太难。
So I'm going to touch on the other form,
所以我将介绍另一种形式，
so we're going to start with that first pentatonic form.
所以我们从第一个五声音阶形式开始。
So take a look at it,
所以看看它，
we're going to start at the fifth fret,
我们将从第五品开始，
in the fifth position, we would call that,
我们称之为第五把位，
so we move our hand up to the fifth position,
所以我们把手移到第五把位，
and I'm going to play through these,
我将弹奏这些，
you'll notice on your chord block or your diagram there,
你们会注意到，在你们的和弦图上，或者你们的图上，
we've got a couple of new concepts,
我们有几个新的概念，
they're all on there,
它们都在那里，
it's not meant to be a chord, it's just a pattern of notes,
它不是一个和弦，它只是一个音符的模式，
but you'll also see a diamond,
但你也会看到一个钻石符号，
the diamond is telling you, that's the major root,
钻石符号告诉你大调根音，
if I'm thinking in major, that's the note I'm pivoting off of,
如果我想要大调，那就是我要用的音符，
the open circle is gonna be the minor root,
开放的圆圈是小调根音，
so with each of these scales,
所以对于每个音阶，
I can think of a major or I can think of a minor.
我都可以想到一个大调，或者一个小调。
Okay, so with this one, it starts with the fifth fret
好的，所以这一个从第五品开始的，
and I'm going to play through it slowly
我会慢慢地弹奏它，
and then I'll talk to you about it.
然后我会和你们讨论它。
Starts on the fifth fret,
从第五品开始，
A and C D E G, A C D E G, A C,
A C D E G, A C D E G, A C ，
okay, now you play with me,
好的，现在你和我一起弹奏，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
let's go down.
我们往下。
Now, you'll notice the minor root, the open circle is on that six string,
你会注意到小调根音，开放的圆圈在六弦上，
A, first finger,
A ，食指，
so this would be an Am pentatonic form,
所以这是一个 Am 五声音阶形式，
so if a song is up
所以如果有一首歌，
and I'm supposed to play Am,
我应该演奏一个 Am ，
I know I can rip off an Am pentatonic
我知道我可以弹出一个 Am 五声音阶，
and I'm going to be in the right key.
我就会达到正确的音调。
Now, but you'll notice the diamond is over this pinky C,
你会注意到钻石符号在小拇指 C 上，
that's if I'm thinking major,
如果我想的是大调，
so if I'm in C major,
如果我在 C 大调，
this song is in C major and I want to play,
我想演奏这首歌是 C 大调的，
I use my pentatonic,
我用五声音阶，
I pivot off of that pinky, C
我从那个小拇指 C 开始，
and that's going to be my major pivot,
这将是我的大调[支点]，
so you get two for the price to want on that.
所以你可以一举两得。
Okay, now let's do it in another place,
好的，现在让我们换个地方，
let's say I wanted a Gm pentatonic,
假设我想要 Gm 五声和弦，
well, the minor root, the open circle is with our first finger,
好的，小调根音，开放的圆圈是我们的食指，
so I put my first finger on G
所以我把我的食指放在 G 上，
and I do that same form again,
我再次做同样的形式，
going down.
往下。
Try a couple more,
再试几个，
what if I wanted, let's say a D major pentatonic,
如果我想要 D 大调五声音阶，
well, I'm not pivoting off of my first finger anymore,
我不再用我的食指，
I'm pivoting off of that pinky,
我要用我的小拇指指，
so I put my pinky on the D, on the sixth string,
所以我把小拇指放在六弦的 D 上，
and I end up with this,
我得到这个，
I don't necessarily have to start with the pinky,
我不一定要从小拇指开始，
I'm just pivoting that just shows me where my form sets,
只是在告诉我，我的形式在哪里，
I still can't start on this,
我仍然不能开始，
would be a D major pentatonic,
这将是 D 大调五声音阶，
also B minor pentatonic.
也是 B 小调五声音阶。
Let's do one more,
让我们再做一个，
let's do it F major pentatonic,
让我们来做 F 大调五声音阶，
well, F major, pivoting off of my pinky,
好的， F 大调，从我的小拇指开始，
well, I can't do F down there,
我不能在那里做 F ，
that gets me out of range,
这会让我超出，
so I've got to go high,
所以我必须往上，
so it be this.
所以是这样。
Now, I would encourage you to go through all these pentatonic forms,
我鼓励你练习所有这些五声音阶形式，
this first one,
第一个，
and if it takes a while to get,
需要一段时间才能达到，
so I would start low, go through it in one place,
我从一个低的地方开始，弹奏它，
then maybe go through a half step higher,
然后往上半音，
I want you to get, you need to get the pattern of it, underneath your fingers,
我想让你得到它的模式，在你手指下面，
the pattern being one four, first finger, fourth finger, first finger, third finger,
模式是， 1 4 ，食指，小拇指，食指，无名指，
one three, one three, one four, one four,
1 3 ， 1 3 ， 1 4 ， 1 4 ，
one four, one three, one three, one three, one four, one four.
1 4 ， 1 3 ， 1 3 ， 1 3 ， 1 4 ， 1 4 。
Okay, so do it in a bunch of different places,
好的，在不同的地方做这个，
you do it ascending or descending,
你可以上升或下降，
you can play it without hesitating,
你可以毫不犹豫弹奏它，
play on that metronome, it's good practice for you,
使用节拍器，对你来说是好的做法，
that's the first pentatonic form.
这是第一个五声音阶形式。
Now there's five,
一共有五个，
let me just briefly cover the next one, the next few,
让我简单地介绍下一个，
the second pentatonic form,
第二个五声音阶形式，
if you'll notice, now the diamond is on my second finger
你注意到，现在钻石符号在我的食指上，
and I've shifted up to the seventh fret,
我已经移到了第七品上，
so this form will be like this,
所以这个形式是这样的，
if I'm playing in C major,
如果我现在演奏 C 大调，
now you may not know what all these notes are up here,
你们可能不知道音符是什么，
upon these upper strings,
在这些上面的弦上，
we haven't really covered those yet,
我们还没有介绍那些，
that's okay, that's the beauty, that's the beautiful thing about patterns finger patterns now.
这是好的，这就是关于形式的优美之处。
So guitar playing is music and knowing all of the notes
所以吉他演奏是音乐，知道所有的音符，
and you need to understand that we've talked a good deal about that,
你需要明白我们已经讨论了很多，
now I'm going to talk about patterns,
现在我要谈的是模式，
a lot of it is just finger patterns,
很多是手指模式，
you can do little finger patterns to get the sound that you want,
你可以做一些手指模式来得到你想要的声音，
you may not necessarily know what note your playing,
你可能不一定知道你演奏的是什么音符，
you should know,
你应该知道，
but at this point, I want you to get used to doing the pattern of it,
但在这一点上，我想你习惯于做它的模式，
you can also say the scale with it,
你也可以说它的音阶，
C D E G A C D E G A C D,
C D E G A C D E G A C D ，
the goal is to learn all of the neck of your guitar,
目标是学习吉他琴颈上的所有，
it may seem unknowable,
这看起来可能是不可知的，
I remember sitting in school thinking,
我记得坐在学校里，我想，
there's no way I could learn this whole neck,
我不可能学到整个琴颈，
pentatonic scales is what solved that problem for me,
五声音阶为我解决了这个问题，
and I'll talk more about that in the guitar tips section,
我将在吉他技巧部分更多地讨论这一点，
in you know a little bit, in the.
稍等片刻。
Let's go through pentatonic form three,
让我们来学习五声音阶模式三，
now, I've got my second finger upon this D,
现在，我让中指在 D 上，
now you'll notice my minor root is down here
你会注意到，我的小调根音在，
on the third, excuse me on the fourth string,
第三，对不起，在第四弦，
no wait a minute, my minor root on the fifth string with my pinky,
不，等一下，我的小调根音在第五弦上，用我的小拇指，
okay, my major root is with my second finger on the third, on the fourth string,
我的大调根音是用食指在第四弦上，
so you'll notice how they're always swapping around,
所以你会注意到它们是如何交换的，
so you gotta keep keep keep them straight in your mind,
所以你必须保持它们在你的头脑中，
this is the third one.
这是第三个。
Okay, let's talk over that fourth form,
我们来讨论第四种形式，
okay, starts up here on this E,
好的，从这个 E 开始，
let's go through it,
我们开始吧，
back down,
退后，
on, leave to work on on your own time.
留给你自己的时间练习。
Let me show you the fifth form,
让我给你们看第五种模式，
now I could do it way up here at the fourteenth fret,
我可以在第十四品做这个，
but that's not what I want to do,
但这不是我想做的，
I'm going to jump down and transpose it down here to the second fret,
我要跳下来，把它转移到第二品，
where it's a little bit more comfortable to play at,
在那里弹奏会更舒服一些，
okay, so the last form, the fifth form is like this.
所以最后一种模式，第五种模式就像这样。
There are five different ways I can play those scales,
我可以用五种不同的方式来弹奏这些音阶，
all you need to do is learn these five forms,
你所需要做的就是学习这五种形式，
they may seem big and and intimidating at first,
它们一开始可能看起来很大，很吓人，
if it's five forms, it's not an unknowable amount of information,
它是五种模式，它不是一个不可知的信息量，
it's five finger patterns,
它是五种手指模式，
you do about a hundred times and you got them,
你做大约一百次，就得到它们，
so it just takes a little bit of a leg work to get them underneath your fingers,
所以只需要一点工作就可以把它们放在你的手指下，
once you get them underneath your fingers,
一旦你把它们放在你的手指下面，
know how to pivot off of them,
知道如何从它们上转动，
you're able to play in any key major or minor.
你就能够弹奏任何音调的大调或小调。
Okay, so I'm going to show you a couple of the common pentatonic patterns that guys use,
好的，我将向你们展示几个常见的五声音阶模式，
okay, that you can incorporate into your soloing,
你可以把它们融入到你的 solo 中，
okay, first one is,
第一个是，
I'm going to go back to our first position A minor pentatonic form
我将回到我们的第一个 A 小调五声音阶形式，
and I'm going to go in groups of four,
我将以四个一组的形式进行，
what do I mean by that,
我说的是什么意思，
well, here we go,
好的，我们开始，
it'd be like one two three four
就像 1 2 3 4 ，
and then I go back down to the C,
然后我回到 C ，
and then I go up four from it,
然后我从它向上四个，
go go the next note D
到下一个音符 D ，
and I go up four from it,
我从它向上四个，
E, four from it and so on.
E ，从它向上四个，等等。
When I get to the top,
当我到达顶端时，
let me just do it ascending first,
让我先往上，
and you can hear what sounds like.
你能听到听起来的声音。
Good, okay, now I'm gonna do it descending,
好的，现在我开始往下，
C A G A,
C A G A ，
I go back up to the A, go down four, from it.
我回到 A ，从它开始四个。
Okay, that's the first form, the first pattern that we're gonna talk about,
好的，这是我们讨论的第一种形式，
the next one we're gonna talk about,
我们要讨论的下一种，
as we go up in groups of three,
我们三个一组向上，
we've gone up in groups of four,
我们已经四个一组向上，
now I'm going to go up in groups of three,
现在我要三个一组向上，
so I would go like, one two three, one two three,
所以我要弹， 1 2 3 ， 1 2 3 。
now go descending.
现在，向下。
Okay, going up in groups of four,
四个一组向上，
going up in groups of three.
三个一组向上。
Okay, now here's a third one that I like to use
现在这是我喜欢用的第三个，
and I'm going up in pairs,
我要成对地向上，
three, three pairs each,
一次三对，
I don't know how to explain that,
我不知道怎么解释，
well, I'm doing three pairs each,
我每次做三对，
let me show you and maybe you can get the idea,
让我演示给你，也许你能明白，
one four, one three, one three,
1 4 ， 1 3 ， 1 3 ，
that would be like the first,
就像第一个，
triplet of pairs,
三对，
then I go one string down and do three more
然后我往下一根弦，再做三对，
and go back one string and do three pairs,
再往下一根弦，再做三对，
back one string, do the next,
往下一根弦，做下一个，
let me do that, from the beginning again,
让我这样做，从头再来，
it's one set of three, two sets of three,
这是第一个三对，第二个三对，
I can do this in reverse descending.
我可以反着来，往下。
Okay, it does it takes a little bit of speeding up,
好的，需要一点速度，
okay, a little distortion on that, maybe a little bit of delay,
好的，加点失真，再加点延时，
crank it down here,
旋转到这里，
a, try again,
再试一次，
okay, so you end up getting some real cool sounds from those,
好的，你会听到一些很酷的声音，
okay, now in order to hear what sound you're going for,
好的，为了听到你要听到的声音，
we're going to train our ear a little bit
我们会训练一下我们的耳朵，
and we're going to do that in the next section,
我们会在下一节这样做，
so I'll see you there.
所以我们在那里见。
Okay, before we delve into the ear training stuff,
好的，在我们深入研究耳朵训练之前，
let's talk about some guitar tips
让我们来谈谈一些吉他技巧，
on how to learn these scales,
关于如何学习这些音阶，
now it's going to take you a while,
现在你需要一段时间，
it took me about three months to get these scales down,
我花了大约三个月的时间才掌握这些音阶，
where I could play him in every key in any place on the neck,
我可以弹奏琴颈上任何地方的每个调，
so it's gonna take a while,
所以这需要一段时间，
but it is well worth it,
但这是非常值得的，
that time that I spent,
我花的那段时间，
taking these scales doing them every day,
每天做这些音阶，
not like I spent ten hours a day,
不是我每天花 10 个小时练习，
I hear these guys spend ten hours a day practicing,
我听说这些家伙每天花 10 个小时练习，
that's great for them,
这对他们很好，
I mean, I get a little bit when I can,
我是说，当我可以的时候，我会做，
I practice when I need to
当我需要的时候，我练习，
and when I can do it,
当我可以做到，
but every day I would try and carve out a little bit of time
但每天我都会试着挤出一点时间，
and I did these pentatonic scales,
我做这些五声音阶，
and I didn't get it the first week,
第一周我没有掌握，
I didn't get the second week,
第二周我没有掌握，
but after slowly, slowly, slowly,
但慢慢地，慢慢地，
I got that skill of connecting these scales together
我获得了将这些音阶连接在一起的技能，
and that changed my whole dynamic of playing,
这改变了我的整个演奏动态，
it's well worth to put the effort into it.
为此付出努力是非常值得的。
Okay, so what do I mean by connecting these scales together,
好的，我说这些音阶连接在一起是什么意思，
well, as you can see by the different forms,
你可以从不同的形式看到，
where one form ends, another form starts,
一个形式结束，另一个形式开始，
so they kind of fit together like puzzle pieces on your guitar,
它们就像吉他上的拼图块一样，
if you can think about it that way,
如果你能这样想的话，
where one side of a pattern,
模式的一边，
the first form, let's say,
比如，第一个形式，
well, these last, that's actually the one side of the next pattern,
最后这个实际上是下一个模式的一边，
sorry, see how that works
抱歉，看到它是如何工作的，
and the next one is the one side of the previous pattern,
下一个是前一个模式的一边，
so they fit together like jigsaw pieces,
所以它们像拼图一样拼凑在一起，
okay, jigsaw puzzle pieces,
拼图游戏，
okay, now knowing this, we can then connect them together,
好的，知道了这一点，我们可以把它们连接在一起，
so one of the most helpful exercises that I started doing,
所以我开始做的一个最有帮助的练习是，
once you get all these forms down
一旦你完成了所有这些形式，
is you start connecting these together,
你就开始把它们连接在一起，
so let's say, I'm starting,
比如，我开始于，
what do I mean by that,
我说的是什么意思，
I'll ascend in one form
我以一种形式上升，
and switch to the next form and descend,
然后切换到下一种形式下降，
like this,
就像这样，
then I'll go up to the next form and descend,
然后我到下一个形式，向下，
and then I'll go shift up to the next form and go back up again,
然后我到下一个形式，再回来，
shift up to next form, go down,,
移动到下一种形式，向下，
shift up to next form, go down, let's go down,
移动到下一种形式，向下，让我们向下，
then end up back where I started again.
最后回到我开始的地方。
Okay, so if I put all those together,
好的，如果我把所有这些放在一起，
it would sound something like this.
它听起来有点像这样。
Now takes a little bit to get the finger pattern, part of that down,
需要一点时间才能掌握手指模式，
but once you do,
但一旦你这样做了，
I can now solo using pentatonic anywhere on the neck,
我可以使用琴颈上任何地方 solo ，
if I want to go high I can go high,
如果我想要高音，我可以去高音，
I've got a pentatonic form that will take me there,
我有一个五声音阶形式可以带我去那里，
if I want to stay low, I've got a pentatonic form,
如果我想保持低音，我有一个五声形式，
I know which notes are safe for me to land on,
我知道哪些音符对我来说是安全的，
if I want, if I want to think about soloing in a finger pattern way,
如果我想用手指模式来 solo ，
rather than using scales and theory,
而不是使用音阶和理论，
we ideally want to use both,
我们理想的是两者都使用，
but if I want to use a finger pattern way,
但如果我想使用手指模式方式，
I know which notes are safe for me to land on
我知道哪些音符对我来说是安全的，
by these pentatonic forms, that are on that.
通过这些五声形式，就在上面。
Let's do it, let's say if I'm in F minor,
我们开始吧，假设我在 F 小调，
okay.
好的。
Okay, now I'm in F minor,
好的，现在我在 F 小调，
I can solo anywhere on the neck
我可以在琴颈上的任何地方 solo ，
and F minor I've got little pictures,
F 小调我有一些图像，
even though I may not know exactly what those notes are,
即使我可能不知道这些音符是什么，
I've got little pictures of patterns,
我有一些模式的图像，
that I can use anywhere on the neck
我可以在琴颈上的任何地方使用，
and that's a big key to do it,
这是一个很大的关键，
so put some effort into it,
所以花点功夫，
connect these scales together,
把这些音阶连接在一起，
keeping in mind which ones are major, which ones are minor,
记住哪些是大调，哪些是小调，
you'll learn how to dance around on them
你会学到如何在使用它们跳舞，
and pentatonic will take you a good long way in your soloing.
五声音阶会带你在 solo 中走很长一段路。
Now, let's talk about some ear training things,
现在，我们来谈谈耳朵训练，
we have not talked about ear training so far,
我们到目前为止还没有讨论过耳朵训练的事情，
so let's kind of get into it,
所以让我们开始吧，
what ear training is,
耳朵训练是什么，
is I want to not just be playing patterns on my guitar,
我想要的不仅仅是在吉他上弹奏模式，
when I'm soloing,
当我 solo 的时候，
I want to actually hear music idea, musical ideas in my head
我想要在我的大脑中听到音乐的想法，
and be able to play them through my guitar.
并能够通过我的吉他弹奏。
Okay, one of the greatest quotes I've ever heard was,
好的，我听过的最伟大的一句话是，
in your head,
在你的脑海里，
it's by Chris Proctor, a great guitarist said,
它是 Chris Proctor ，一个伟大的吉他手所说的，
in your head is every musical idea you've ever heard,
在你的脑海里，你听过的每一个音乐想法，
but your fingers will only do what they've been trained to do,
但你的手指只会做它们被训练过的事情，
so you need to,
所以你需要，
we're working on training our fingers,
我们训练我们的手指，
so just as we hear in our head,
所以就像我们在脑海中听到的一样，
it takes a little bit of sitting on our bed trying to figure out that [],
我们需要坐在床上试着弄清楚这种[]，
so when we need to rip it out, we can play it,
所以当我们需要把它[撕下来]的时候，我们可以弹奏它，
so we're going to practice some ear training things
所以我们要练习一些耳朵训练的东西，
to talk about some simple different ways,
来谈论一些简单的不同的方式，
we're going to start on that first pentatonic form,
我们从第一个五声音阶开始，
I'm going to play a simple idea,
我将弹奏一个简单的想法，
and you try and play it back to me,
你试着把它重新弹奏出来，
we're using that first, first pentatonic form in A minor,
我们使用的第一个五声音阶形式是 A 小调，
I'm gonna play some simple ideas,
我将弹奏一些简单的想法，
let's, let's click on our metronome here,
让我们打开这里的节拍器，
I'm gonna play some simple ideas
我要弹奏一些简单的想法，
and you try and play them back to me, okay?
你试着把它们重新弹奏出来，好吗？
I'm gonna start on this low A,
我将从这个低音 A 开始，
we'll get start real simple,
我们开始非常简单，
ready, go, one two three four,
准备，开始， 1 2 3 4 ，
now you play that note,
现在你弹奏那个音符，
what about this,
这样怎么样，
you play a note,
你弹奏一个音符，
now you play that,
现在你弹奏这个，
what about this,
这个怎么样，
trying to get a little bit,
试着得到一点，
let's do that one again,
让我们再来一次，
kind of slid into a little bit there,
有点滑到那里了，
now you try and play.
现在你试着弹奏。
Good, see how that works,
好的，看到这是如何起作用的，
simple ear training exercises like that,
像这样的简单耳朵训练练习，
we'll do more, when we get to the workshop time,
当我们到达 workshop 时间的时候，我们会做更多，
try and pick out little melodic ideas
试着挑出旋律上的想法，
and try and figure them out on your guitar,
试着在你的吉他上找出它们，
hunt and peck form
找到形式，
until you can actually get them,
直到你找到它们，
then do them do another key
然后用另一个调弹奏它们，
try and transpose
试着转调，
and try and do an octave lower an octave higher,
试着低八度，高八度，
a different place on the neck,
在琴颈上的不同位置，
that's how you train your ear
这就是你如何训练你的耳朵，
to when you hear an idea in your head
当你在你的脑海中听到一个想法时，
to be able to play it through your fingers,
能够通过你的手指演奏它，
it's a little bit of trial and error
这是一个小小的尝试和错误，
and doing simple things like that,
做一些简单的事情，
you hear a note, you try and play,
你听到一个音符，你试着弹奏，
you hear an idea,
你听到一个想法，
maybe you hear a phrase off the radio off the song that you like,
也许你从收音机里听到了你喜欢的歌曲中的一个片段，
get your guitar and try and figure out what that was,
拿起你的吉他，试着弄清楚那是什么，
try and play it,
试着弹奏它，
it's got a lot of trial and error at first,
一开始有很多尝试和错误，
but eventually you'll start picking the right notes more and more of the time
但最终你会越来越多地开始挑选正确的音符，
and that's what it's all about.
这就是它的全部意义。
Okay, your assignment for this week is
好的，本周的作业是
to practice all the pentatonic forms that we have in the book,
练习我们在书中的所有五声音阶形式，
there's five of them,
这里有五个，
don't just do the first one,
不要只做第一个，
do these other four as well.
其他四个也要做。
Okay, very on the neck where you're placing these pentatonic forms,
好的，在琴颈上你放置五声音阶形式，
take them ascending, take them descending,
让它们上升，让它们下降，
and for extra credit,
为了获得额外的[学分]，
if you really want to get him down,
如果你想让它下降，
do that exercise I talked about in the guitar tips,
做我在吉他技巧中提到的练习，
connect them all together go ascending and descending,
把它们连接在一起，上升和下降，
do it in every key all over the neck,
在琴颈上的每个调上都是这样，
there's only 12 keys,
只有 12 个调，
wow, it's a big assignment, I know it is,
哇，这是一项艰巨的任务，
but it will help you learn the entire neck of your instrument,
但它将帮助你学习乐器的整个琴颈，
be thinking about what notes they are,
想想它们是什么音符，
try and say and play them,
试着说，然后弹奏它们，
while you're doing it,
当你在做的时候，
it's very difficult at first,
刚开始的时候很难，
as you get it,
一旦你掌握，
you will learn and master this whole part of the neck
你会学习和掌握琴颈的整个部分，
with being able to solo
可以 solo ，
and it's a great thing to try and do,
这是一件很棒的事情，
so I'll see you at the workshop time.
我会在 workshop 上见到你。
Okay, welcome to the workshop time,
好的，欢迎来到 workshop 时间，
here's where we get it all done at,
在这里我们可以完成所有的工作，
we're going to talk about the pentatonic forms,
我们会讨论五声音阶形式，
we're going to go over that first one first,
我们会先复习第一个，
that A minor pentatonic,
那个 A 小调五声音阶，
I'm going to put on my handy [] metronome,
我会打开手边的节拍器，
started nice and slow.
开始的很好，很慢。
We're going at first form,
我们首先做第一个形式，
A minor or C major pentatonic,
A 小调或 C 大调五声音阶，
depending on how you want to look at it,
取决于你想怎么看，
here we go, one two, ready go,
我们开始， 1 2 ，准备开始，
let's go down,
让我们向下，
let's do it again, one two, you know what to do.
让我们再做一次， 1 2 ，你知道该怎么做，
Great, now let's do it,
好的，现在我们来做，
let's say if I wanted to do it in a G minor,
假设我想做一个 G 小调，
where I need to put my first finger on that third fret G
我需要把我的食指放在第三品 G 上，
and do the same thing again,
然后做同样的事情，
let's speed it up a little bit,
让我们加快一点，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
what about C minor,
C 小调呢，
C minor, find it,
C 小调，找到它，
that eight fret, ready, go.
在第八品，准备，开始。
Okay, now let's try a different exercise,
好的，现在让我们尝试一个不同的练习，
we're gonna do that first position,
我们要做第一把位，
we're going to do that first form said we're going to do it down in the first position
我们要做第一个形式在第一把位，
and let me click on a little bit of distortion
让我加一点失真，
just to give us a different sound,
给我们一个不同的声音，
and we're going to do this,
我们会做这个，
well, I'll explain along as we go,
好的，随着我们进行，我会解释这个，
start down here at the F minor pentatonic,
从 F 小调开始，
I'm gonna do it,
我从它开始，
ascending and descending
上升和下降，
and then we're going to shift up a half step,
然后我们要向上移动半音，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
I don't know why this wasn't working right,
我不知道这为什么不能正常工作，
I don't have my metronome going,
我的节拍器没有正常工作，
there we go, let's speed it up just a little bit,
好了，让我们把速度加快一点，
okay, F minor, ready go,
好的， F 小调，准备，开始，
let's shift up a half step,
让我们向上半音，
up a half step,
向上半音，
let's go up half step now
现在向上半音，
and we're gonna descend, a half step up,
我们要往下，向上半音，
so we're gonna go down this time,
所以这次我们要向下，
up,
向上，
up.
向上。
Good, all right, now let's do the other second pentatonic form,
好的，现在让我们做第二个五声音阶形式，
okay, start on a C major,
好的，从 C 大调开始，
so this is up here at the seventh fret,
这在第七品上，
your second finger at the eighth fret,
你的食指在第八品，
but the position is seventh position,
但是位置是第七把位，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
what I wanted to play a G major pentatonic in that second form,
如果我想在第二种形式下弹奏 G 大调五声音阶，
where would you need to go,
你需要去哪里，
well, the pivot notes on that second finger,
好的，[枢轴]音符在食指上，
so I put my second finger on that G
所以我把我的食指放在那个 G 上，
and I'm ready to go,
我准备好了，
ready play,
准备，弹奏，
let's go back
让我们回去，
and let's do some of those pentatonic patterns
让我们来做一些五声音阶模式，
that we talked about in the first part.
我们在第一部分中谈到的。
Okay, so let's go back to our A minor pentatonic first position
好的，让我们回到 A 小调五声音阶，第一个位置，
and we're going to do going up by fours,
我们要做的是四个一组，
going up four notes at a time,
一次弹奏四个音符，
ready play.
准备，弹奏。
Okay, let's crank it up a little bit,
好的，让我们稍微调高一点，
we're going to start right where we stopped off
我们将从我们停止的地方开始，
and then we're gonna go back down using four, four to a pattern,
然后我们将使用四个一组模式，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Now, let's do the pattern with three,
现在让我们做第三个模式，
okay, let's go up to, let's say a C minor pentatonic,
好的，让我们上升到 C 小调五声音阶，
we're going to go up in thirds or three to a set,
我们将以三个一组，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
okay, just for fun,
好的，为了好玩，
let's crank it way up and do the same thing again,
我们把它调高，做同样的事情，
three to, three to a set,
三个一组，
one, ready go.
1 ，准备，开始。
Great, okay, last thing I want to cover on our workshop time is,
很好，在我们的 workshop 时间，我想讲的最后一件事是，
we're going to connect those scales together,
我们要把这些音阶连接在一起，
so let's start down,
所以让我们从，
let's start down here F minor,
让我们从 F 小调开始，
which would be Ab major
也是 Ab 大调，
and we're going to connect these scales together,
我们将把这些音阶连接在一起，
ascending and descending all over the length of the neck.
在整个琴颈的长度上向上和向下。
Okay, let's slow it down a little bit,
好的，让我们放慢速度，
okay, one two, ready go,
好的， 1 2 ，准备，开始，
now shift up in the next form, come down,.
现在换到下一种形式，向下。
Great, okay, that gives you something to practice on,
好的，这给了你们一些可以练习的东西，
I would encourage you to work a little bit more on your own time
我鼓励你在自己的时间多练习一点，
to get the things you need to get down.
获得你需要的东西。
Okay, so that's a bit of practice on pentatonics,
好的，所以这是对五声音阶的一些练习，
pentatonics is going to change the way that you play,
五声音阶将改变你的演奏方式，
just like a changed man
就像改变了一个人一样，
and a whole other dimension to what you're doing,
和你正在做的事情完全不同，
so we'll see you next time.
所以我们下一次再见。